Triumphant in Victory, Bitter in Defeat. He
Changed the World, But Lost a Nation.
Nixon is a drama, history film directed by Oliver Stone.
A look at President Richard M.
Nixon—a man carrying the fate of the world on his shoulders while battling the self-destructive demands from
within—spanning his troubled boyhood in California to the shocking Watergate scandal that would end his Presidency.
Richard Nixon, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Pat Nixon, played by Joan Allen.
Alexander Haig, played by Powers Boothe.
E. Howard Hunt, played by Ed Harris.
J. Edgar Hoover, played by Bob Hoskins.
John Mitchell, played by E.G. Marshall.
Nixon is a 1995 American epic historical drama film directed by Oliver
Stone, produced by Stone, Clayton Townsend, and Andrew G.
Vajna, and written by Stone, Christopher Wilkinson, and Stephen J.
It tells the story of the political and personal life of former U.S.
President Richard Nixon, played by Anthony Hopkins.
The film portrays Nixon as a complex and in many respects
admirable, albeit deeply flawed, person.
Nixon begins with a disclaimer that the film is "an
attempt to understand the truth ...
based on numerous public sources and on an incomplete historical record".
The cast also includes Joan Allen, Annabeth Gish,
Marley Shelton, Bai Ling, Powers Boothe, J.
Marshall, Sam Waterston, James Woods, Paul Sorvino, Bob Hoskins, Larry Hagman, Ed Harris, and David Hyde Pierce, plus archival
appearances from political figures such as President Bill Clinton in television footage from the Nixon funeral service.
The film received generally favorable reviews from critics, with
Hopkins' performance receiving particular praise.
Despite this, the film grossed only $13.6 million domestically against a $44
million budget, making it one of the biggest box-office bombs of 1995.
The film was nominated for four Academy Awards: Best Actor (Anthony Hopkins), Best Supporting
Actress (Joan Allen), Best Original Score (John Williams) and Best Original Screenplay.
This was Stone's second of three films about the presidents of the United
States, after JFK, which was about the assassination of John F.
Kennedy, and W., which was about George W.
The film explores themes of usa president, washington dc,
usa, government, presidential election, 1970s.
The tone is emotional.